Denise Ortega

I am a detail-oriented, design-driven full stack web developer. My background as an engineer allows me to approach problems abstractly and conquer them efficiently, while my experience as a program manager allows me to plan and implement for scale, while setting realistic goals.

Seattle, WA, dddotcom@gmail.com

LinkedIn: /ddortega Github: /dddotcom URL: dddotcom.github.io

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, SQL, Bash

Tools: Express, Angular, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Node, Git. Heroku. Bootstrap

Experience

Microsoft, Redmond, WA - Program Manager

Aug 2015 - Oct 2016

Design and oversee implementation of a Cloud Infrastructure deployment tool. Meet with subject-matter-experts to accurately document the infrastructure deployment process flow. Help prioritize engineering work, engage with stakeholders to track progress, and verify completeness

Lumenpulse, Boston, MA - Application Developer

Nov 2014 - May 2015

Develop an Android application that controls the brightness/color of Lumenpulse light fixtures over Bluetooth Low Energy. Test the functionality and user experience with the customer before the app was revealed at Lightfair 2015.

MITRE, Bedford, MA - Cyber Infrastructure Intern

May 2014 - Nov 2014

Develop a Grails web application that provisions Virtual Machines automatically. The application eliminates ambiguous VM requests and increases VM provisioning throughput through automation.

CIDAR Lab, Boston, MA - Software Developer

May 2014 - Nov 2014

Work with a team to develop a Java application for automating Synthetic Biology protocols. Devised a graph algorithm that uses custom data structures to accurately schedule and reserve laboratory equipment.

Projects

Tanya Wenya Teens, - Web based two-player game

A game inspired by Tenya Wanya Teens, built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Phaser.io. TWT is a two player game where players race to complete daily tasks such as brushing teeth or playing guitar.

The Guardian, - Senior Capstone Project

Worked with a team to create a baby monitoring system. Built using a raspberry pi, temperature sensors, and a raspicam that streams live video to a Rails application. Responsible for implementing the communication layer between the devices and web application. Designed and implemented an efficient live-streaming solution, minimizing playback latency to 5-7 seconds.

Education

General Assembly, Seattle, WA

February 2017 - April 2017

A full time, 12-week course teaching programming fundamentals and skills to build full-stack web applications.

Boston University, Boston, WA - Computer Engineering BS

January 2012 - May 2015